Don Yoder collection of tape and disc recordings
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 2: Sound Recordings
  - Sound recording, March 10, 1961, RAA 46894; 1 sound tape reel (00:30:52): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR060)
    Clarence Wagner (born January 2, 1879) sings revival songs in Pennsylvania German. Don Yoder can be heard in background.
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46895; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:30:13, Side B: 00:27:32): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR061)
    A series of interviews on healing. Steve Diamond (a student at the University of Pennsylvania) interviews several people. An unidentified man is interviewed in person, followed by another unidentified man, Mrs. White, Rev. Best, and Sister Lilah [?]. All but the first person were interviewed by phone. The audio speed seems slow at times.
    A series of interviews on healing. Steve Diamond (a student at the University of Pennsylvania) may have conducted the interviews. Included are Raymond Charles Barker (possibly dubbed from another recording), and a phone interview with an unidentified man.
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46896; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:48:42, Side B: 00:27:59): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR062)
    One interview or more on healing; see SR061. Part of this recording may have been dubbed from another recording. Steve Diamond (a student at the University of Pennsylvania) may have conducted the interviews. Included is a phone interview with Bishop Moody. Traffic noise can be heard during the interview. Audio cuts off abruptly at the end of the recordings.
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46897; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:33:13, Side B: 00:26:33): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR063)
    A church service, plus interviews on healing. This recording may have been made over another recording: during very quiet portions a woman can be heard speaking. Steve Diamond (a student at the University of Pennsylvania) conducted the interview of an unidentified man. At 00:27:29 Steve Diamond interviews an unidentified man. 00:30:13-00:32:29 is a silent portion of audio. The recording cuts off abruptly at the end.
    Interview on healing. This recording may have been made over another recording: during very quiet portions a woman can be heard speaking. Steve Diamond (a student at the University of Pennsylvania) conducted the interview with an unidentified woman associated with St. Stephen's (church).
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46898; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:30:03, Side B: 00:30:33): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR064)
    Steve Diamond (student, University of Pennsylvania) interviews at least three people about healing and Christian Science. Audio cuts off at the end of the interview.
    Steve Diamond interviews two or more people about faith and healing. The first man is a minister of the Triumph, The Church of the New Age. The second is Dr. Elizabeth Hoff. Following the interviews is a dubbed recording of a church service (probably a radio broadcast).
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46899; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:31:40, Side B: 00:04:25): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR065)
    Includes a radio broadcast of a church service, with Rev. Ike. Audio distortion may be a result of the audio levels being too high during the original recording. The audio cuts off before the end of the recording.
    Includes a radio broadcast of a church service.
  - Sound recording, undated, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR066)
    Archivist's note: the tape is entirely blank tape (no content). No information available on what the content may have been
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46901; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:30:21, Side B: 00:20:46): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR067)
    Probably a dub of prerecorded music. Problems with the quality of the audio develop towards the end of the recording.
    Probably a dub of prerecorded music. The audio volume is low for approximately the last ten minutes of the recording.
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46902; 1 sound tape reel (01:04:25): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR068)
    Singing, with at least one song is in Pennsylvania German. One song begins "I'm an honest Irish lad." A dub of a wire recording begins at 00:31:33.
  - Sound recording, July 5-6, 1952, RAA 46903; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:29:55, Side B: 00:29:56): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR069)
    A program, possibly at a festival. Square dance music, and a man speaking in Pennsylvania German. The recording continues on SR069, Side B. The source recording is cut off at the beginning.
    A man gives a sermon and a prayer in Pennsylvania German. At 00:02:27 Don Yoder introduces part of program on witchcraft (black magic) and powwowing (white magic). At 00:03:34 Aunt Sophia Bailer speaks. The recording continues from SR069, Side A.
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46904; 1 sound tape reel (00:23:22): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR070)
    A compilation of selections from recorded interviews, possibly by Steve Diamond, with added introductions.
  - Sound recording, 1979 or before, RAA 46905; 1 sound tape reel (00:16:54): analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR071)
    African American church service; dubbed from the master recording of the Chapman Family Gospel Record. This copy came from the Center for Southern Folklore, Memphis, Tennessee.
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46906; 1 sound tape reel (00:16:31): analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR072)
    An unidentified African American woman recounts religious experiences. The recording includes singing. This tape was dubbed from the master recording of the Chapman Family Gospel Record. This copy came from the Center for Southern Folklore, Memphis, Tennessee.
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46907; 1 sound tape reel (Side A, part 1: 00:26:23, Side A, part 2: 0:01:14, Side B: 00:20:35): analog, 3 3/4 ips (Side A, part 1 and Side B) and 7 1/2 ips (Side A, part 2), half track, mono; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR073)
    Digitization note: six splice points wore out during the transfer. The points were reattached and the transfer was completed.
    Side A, part 1
    Interview of Rabbi Isaac Forman (originally from Poland; d. 1960), on Jewish beliefs and practices. Following a long audio silence, the recording continues with unrelated content: an unidentified woman sings a section from the song "Getting to Know You," from the musical "The King and I." The same woman (or possibly another) sings; the tape speed slows down considerably.
    Side A, part 2
    An unidentified woman sings a section from the song "Getting to Know You," from the musical, "The King and I." The playback or the original recording was made at the wrong speed (too fast). This recording overlaps from sr073a_pt1. The same woman (or possibly another) sings the song "Laura."
    Oral memoirs of a [?], Philadelphia; Jewish history.
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46908; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:11:03, Side B: 00:04:30): analog, 7 1/2 ips (Side A) and 3 3/4 ips (Side B), half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR074)
    An African American Baptist church service. An unidentified woman announces the slate for the recording. Dub copy of a recording, with distortion from the source tape. The audio cuts off at the end of the recording.
    Possibly music recorded from a radio broadcast. The recording has instances of distortion, and is cut off at the end.
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46909; 1 sound tape reel (00:15:19): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR075)
    14th annual Pennsylvania Dutch Festival; Kutztown, Pennsylvania. Don Yoder announces the event. An unidentified man and woman speak. At one point the woman speaks about making corn mush. A child recites poetry.
    Digitization note: several splices wore out during digitization. Points were reattached and the transfer was completed.
  - Sound recording, undated, RAA 46910; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 01:04:17, Side B: 01:04:10): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR076)
    Korean shamanic chant.
    00:00:03 Vocal performance by a female singer, with instrument accompaniment (Korean oboe Taepyŏngso, hourglass Korean drum changku)
    00:02:31 Performance by a female singer (a shaman). Alternation of vocal narration (chanting) and instrumental performance (small bells pangul, hourglass Korean drum, Korean oboe, cymbal); a part of shaman ritual
    00:25:04 Long instrumental introduction (big gong ching, small gongs Kkwaekwari, hourglass drum), alternation of instrumental performance and vocal performance by a female singer (narration in dialect of eastern area and singing: contents—best wish to ancestor for good life)
    00:46:35 Alternation of instrumental introduction (hourglass drum, small gongs, and big gong) and vocal ensemble of several female singers
    01:00:13 Announcement of a male singer, and singing with hourglass drum and small gongs: songs about what the lights used and means in the harvest festival in the city called Kangwŏn in Korea
    00:00:03 Vocal singing by a female singer, with instruments accompaniment (hourglass drum and big gong)
    00:15:55 Vocal chanting by several female singers, with instrument accompaniment (Korean barrel drum puk, big gong)
    00:28:54 Buddhist chanting by two male singers in call and response form, accompanied by instruments (wooden idiophone, moktak)
    00:50:36 Performance by a female singer: vocal narrative genre (Simchyŏng) with instrumental accompaniment (Korean flute taekŭm, barrel drum)
  - Sound recording, April 27, 1979, RYJ 4333; 1 sound cassette (00:13:40): analog, 1 7/8 ips, half track, stereo (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR077)
    Recorded at the "Symposium on Rural Hymnody," hosted by Berea College, April 27-29, 1979. Session A, Part 7 (end of session). Open discussion between symposium participants. Interview with two or three men, possibly including George Carroll, on shape-note singing.
  - Sound recording, April 28, 1979, RYJ 4334; 1 sound cassette (Side A: 00:28:10, Side B: 00:30:04): analog, 1 7/8 ips, half track (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR078)
    Recorded at the "Symposium on Rural Hymnody," hosted by Berea College, April 27-29, 1979. Symposium recordings continue on SR079-SR081.
    Session B, part 1: "Joshua Leavitt's Christian Lyre and Other Developments of Revival Hymnody in the North," presented by Alan Beuchner. Introduction by William H. Tallmadge. The sound cuts off at the end, and the recording continues on SR078, Side B.
    Session B, part 2 continues from part 1. Conclusion on SR079, Side A.
  - Sound recording, April 28, 1979, RYJ 4335; 1 sound cassette (Side A: 00:31:00, Side B: 00:30:30): analog, 1 7/8 ips, half track (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR079)
    Recorded at the "Symposium on Rural Hymnody," hosted by Berea College, April 27-29, 1979.
    Session B, part 3. Alan Buechner finishes his talk. The respondent James C. Downey, William Carey College. Problems with the audio set-up occur, after which Dorothy D. Horn gives her paper: "Jackson's White and Negro Spirituals: Thirty-six Years Later." Conclusion on SR79, Side B.
    Session B, part 4. Dorothy D. Horn finishes her presentation. William H. Tallmadge is the respondent. Portia K. Maultsby gives a paper on "Black Spirituals: Black Aesthetic Concept." Ccontinued on SR080, Side A). The audio cuts off at the end.
  - Sound recording, April 28, 1979, RYJ 4336; 1 sound cassette (Side A: 00:31:11, Side B: 00:30:25): analog, 1 7/8 ips, half track (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR080)
    Session B, part 5: Portia K. Maultsby continues giving her paper, which began on SR079, Side B and concludes on SR080, Side B. The audio cuts off at the end.
    Session B, part 6: Portia K. Maultsby concludes her paper (continued from SR080, Side A). The respondents are Melonee Burnin and Robert Stephens. William Tallmadge presents on "The Black in Jackson's White Spirituals." The audio cuts off at the end.
  - Sound recording, April 28, 1979, RYJ 4337; 1 sound cassette (00:19:56): analog, 1 7/8 ips, half track (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR081)
    Session B, part 7: Tallmadge finishes his presentation. Respondant: Portia K. Maultsby. Session B concludes.
  - Sound recording, March 21, 1976, RYJ 4338; 1 sound cassette (Side A: 00:45:15, Side B: 00:29:38): analog, 1 7/8 ips, half track, mono (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR082)
    Ana Alvarez conducts an informal interview with Olga (no last name given; interview conducted in Spanish and English). Continued on SR083. The recording was probably created as part of an assignment for one of Don Yoder's classes.
  - Sound recording, April 11, 1976, RYJ 4339; 1 sound cassette (Side A: 00:30:23, Side B: 00:17:40): analog, 1 7/8 ips, quarter track, mono (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR083)
    Ana Alvarez interviews Olga (in Spanish and English).
  - Sound recording, December 18, 1970, RYJ 4340; 1 sound cassette (Side A: 00:45:44, Side B: 00:45:51): analog, 1 7/8 ips, half track, mono (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR084)
    Lynne Gorson interviews Clem Tamburrino, a faith healer. The recording was created as part of an assignment for Don Yoder's Religious Thought 523 class.
  - Sound recording, circa Spring 1980, RYJ 4341; 1 sound cassette (Side A: 00:40:58, Side B: 00:20:21): analog, 1 7/8 ips, half track, mono (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR085)
    Interviews introduced by Karen Creuziger. Submitted for Don Yoder's Folk Religion class, Spring 1980.
    The first introduction and interview is with Gene Bissell, on astrology. The second introduction and interview begins at 00:20:28, and is with Jan Rosenberg.
    Introduction by Karen Creuziger, followed by an interview with Jim Putman, on astrology. The interview was recorded over the telephone, which affects the audio quality.
  - Sound recording, circa 1978, RYJ 4342; 1 sound cassette (Side A: 00:30:04, Side B: 00:28:45): analog, 1 7/8 ips, quarter track, mono (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR086)
    Sharon (no surname given) interviews Marie Serpico [?], possibly her grandmother, on Catholicism. There are brief, occasional interruptions from prerecorded music (the tape may have been used before). Interview concludes on SR086, Side B. The recording was probably created as part of an assignment for one of Don Yoder's classes.
    Conclusion of the interview from SR086, Side A, at 00:00:50. The content that follows is out of scope for the collection: audio noise from 00:00:50 to 00:01:11, followed by dubs of commercially released music from the 1970s.
  - Sound recording, undated, RYJ 4343; 1 sound cassette (Side A: 00:15:55, Side B: 00:15:57): analog, 1 7/8 ips, half track, mono (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR087)
    Dub compilation of sermons.
    Oral chanted(?) sermons. The sound levels are very low. Discernable content on Side A ends at 00:13:28, and on Side B ends at 00:15:46.
  - Sound recording, 1971 or before, RXF 7097; 1 sound tape reel (00:41:24): analog, half track, mono; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR088)
    Recordings of Johnny Brendel, of Reinholds, Pennsylvania, and William Brown, of Klingerstown, Pennsylvania. Brendel was a renowned folklorist, and Brown was a well-known Pennsylvania Dutch performer.
    Because of a problem with the source audio, nothing can be heard from about 00:05:23 to 00:05:53; at other points in the recording, the audio is very low, and at times inaudible.
  - Sound recording, no later than 1955, RXF 7098; 1 sound tape reel (01:07:21): analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR089)
    Hegins recordings: Aggie (Bressler) Osman, Valeria (Frymoyer) Gable, and Emma Yoder.
    Occasionally, the audio is very low and at times inaudible. From about 00:30:08 to 00:30:11, ground hum interferes with the program and makes it inaudible. The source recording is likely a dub copy made from other recordings.
  - Sound recording, undated, RXF 6781; 1 sound tape reel (00:29:41): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR090)
    Table graces (or "tischgebete").
    Occasionally, the audio is very low and at times inaudible. Around the 00:29:00, a high-pitched beep can be heard.
  - Sound recording, undated, RXF 6780; 1 sound tape reel (00:15:09): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR091)
    Pennsylvania Dutch (Pennsylvania German) songs by Milton Kuhns; some with piano accompaniment. Some selections are spoken-word. At least two songs are in English.
    At the beginning, there is some sound distortion from the source recording.
  - Sound recording, September 1, 1961, RXF 6779; 1 sound tape reel (00:28:19): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR092)
    Folksongs and prayers. Recorded at the 1st Pennsylvania Dutch Harvest Frolic. The first singer is Marvin Wetzel, second singer (at about 00:06:26) is Ferris Herzog (?), the third and fourth singers (about 00:09:26) are Mabel Snyder and Mary Dannehauer.
    Sound problems with the source recording: repeated instances of bumping or other close contact with the microphone. A high-pitched squeal involving the equipment can be heard from about 00:19:16 to 00:19:21.
  - Sound recording, undated, RXF 7451; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:31:47, Side B: 00:28:06): analog, 3 3/4 ips; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR093)
    "Religion and Music"; a lecture by Don Yoder. According to accompanying documentation, this is "a favorite lecture of Don Yoder's." However, there is no lecture on either tape side. Both tape sides are dubbed from various recordings, including vocal performances (including sacrad harp and Shaker song) by various groups, a sermon given by an African American minister, and an African American spiritual, and other styles of religious song, occasionally with instrumental accompaniment.
  - Sound recording, October 13 or 14, 1972, RXF 7452; 1 sound tape reel (01:32:54): analog, 1 3/8 ips; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR094)
    Interview with Henry Cronister (b. 1881, at Martha Furnace, Centre County). Recorded at Marion Cronister's, Port Matilda, Centre County.
  - Sound recording, October 9, 1968, RXF 7453; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:33:57, Side B: 00:05:07): analog, 3 3/4 ips; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR095)
    Recorded the night John A. Hostetler and Don Yoder stayed at Peachey's farmhouse, RR #1, Belleville, Big Valley (Kishacoquillas Valley), Pennsylvania. See SR009.
    Further notes appear on accompanying documentation.
    00:00:02 We're going home to glory (English song; he wants to have notations made for it)
    00:01:42 Introductory words before performing Ein vermahnungs Lied
    00:02:26 Ein vermahnungs Lied (Ausbund, p. 793); verses 1 and 4 (slow tune)
    00:05:21 Hostetler explains that Hirtz used to repeated much of that chapter almost every Sunday he preached, on the duty of unity, harmony, and humility. Hostetler speaks at length in Pennsylvania German. Scripture readings and devotional exercises in the morning held at the Peachey home.
    00:17:47 Examples of the fast songs (with introductions): Wedding hymn ("Dinne Buch," p. 204, or in Yoder, p. 456), In der Stillen Einsamkeit (#59 in Yoder), Wo ist Jesus Mein Verlangen (#62 in Yoder), Nun Gott Lob es ist Vollbracht (#173 in "Binne Buch"). The program ends about 00:33:30
    00:00:01 Table Hymn ("Funf Tausend Menschen speisest Du"), sung by Samuel, his wife Julia, and daughter Sara Peachey
    0:00:51 Song for morning family worship (sung by Samuel, his wife Julia, and daughter Sara Peachey)
    00:03:17 When Love Shines In (English song), sung by Samuel, his wife Julia, and daughter Sara Peachey
    00:04:41 Audio ends
  - Sound recording, undated, RXF 7454; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:22:53, Side B: 00:32:26): analog; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR096)
    Singing of Indiana Amish, recorded by John A. Hostetler. The recording includes the 42nd Psalm, Luterbach [?], with yodeling; "Oh Where Is [sic] My Little Dog Gone," with yodeling, and other songs with yodeling. There are several gaps in the program; the longest gap is from about 00:07:21 to about 00:18:01, from the source recording, and followed by testing.
    An elderly woman (maiden name: Elizabeth Swartz) is interviewed and also sings. There are other speakers and singers. About 00:23:41 there is yodeling. About 00:02:45, a train or truck with a horn can be heard passing by. There are some gaps between cuts (seemingly long pauses between sections of the recording).
  - Sound recording, 1971 or before, RXF 7455; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 01:07:25, Side B: 00:39:27): analog; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR097)
    Reminiscences of Foster Piper, the son of a Methodist preacher, in the Dutch County (Millheim, Centre County).
    Millheim, Centre County, was all Pennsylvania Dutch then, and as a boy he tried to learn Pennsylvania German. Foster became a distinguished Methodist preacher, in the East New York Conference.
  - Sound recording, undated, RXF 7456; 1 sound tape reel (00:30:45): analog; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR098)
    A compilation of various groups singing different types of American hymnody, probably dubbed from commercial sound discs. According to accompanying documentation, this is a tape of American Folk Hymnody, compiled by John D. Boyd. "Joe" Boyd was from Texas, and an editor of the Farm Journal. He studied with Don Yoder.
  - Sound recording, circa 1967, RXF 7457; 1 sound tape reel (00:34:14): analog; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR099)
    A compilation of various groups singing different types of American hymnody, possibly from both commercial and non-commercial sources. Includes sacred harp singing. According to accompanying documentation, this tape was made for American Folk Hymnody by Archie Green. Archie Green was a member of Don Yoder's first class of "Folk Studies" at the University of Pennsylvania in 1967.
  - Sound recording, circa 1961, RXF 7458; 1 sound tape reel (Side A: 00:13:32, Side B: 00:19:13): analog, 7 1/2 ips; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR100)
    Emma Yoder singing. She was Don Yoder's aunt; the older sister of Yoder's father. Songs include "Dutch choruses" (revival songs).
    Clarence Wagner (1873-1961), of Annville, Pennsylvania, singing religious songs in Pennsylvania German. About 00:17:29 a woman can be heard singing; it is probably Emma Yoder.
  - Sound recording, undated, RXF 7459; 1 sound tape reel (00:41:20): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR101)
    Recording of Johnny Brendle and Willy Brown, entirely in Pennsylvania German. From the accompanying notes: Johnny Brendel had a Dutch radio program. According to Don Yoder, Willy Brown of Mahantongo (Mahantongo Valley) was the most prolific Dutch singer he recorded.
  - Sound recording, December 10, 1977, RXH 0745; 1 sound tape reel (00:29:03): analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR102)
    Don Yoder gives a lecture, primarily in Pennsylvania German, ending about 00:27:07. The musical piece that follows the lecture seems unrelated, and may indicate the lecture was taped over another recording. The lecture was recorded in Bern, Switzerland.
  - Sound recording, undated, RXH 0746; 1 sound tape reel (00:24:03): analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/051: SR103)